The magic of friendship never changes.
My Little Pony: Equestria Girls is a animation, comedy,
family film directed by Jayson Thiessen.
Via a magic mirror, Twilight Sparkle travels into an alternate universe in
order to recover a crown that was stolen from the Crystal Empire.
Upon her arrival she is horrified to learn that she has turned into a human.
Twilight Sparkle (voice), played by Tara Strong.
Applejack / Rainbow Dash (voice), played by Ashleigh Ball.
Pinkie Pie / Fluttershy (voice), played by Andrea Libman.
Rarity / Princess Luna / Vice Principal Luna / Cup Cake
(voice), played by Tabitha St. Germain.
Spike (voice), played by Cathy Weseluck.
Sunset Shimmer (voice) / Twilight Sparkle  (singing
voice), played by Rebecca Shoichet.
My Little Pony: Equestria Girls is a 2013 animated musical fantasy film directed by Jayson Thiessen, written by
Meghan McCarthy, and produced by DHX Media Vancouver for Hasbro Studios in the United States.
It is the first installment in Hasbro's Equestria Girls franchise, which serves as
an anthropomorphic spin-off to the 2010 relaunch of My Little Pony.
The film and franchise's introduction also commemorates the 30th
anniversary of the original My Little Pony toy line.
Equestria Girls re-envisions the main characters of its parent franchise, normally
ponies, as teenage humanoid characters in a high school setting.
Set between the third and fourth seasons of the My Little Pony: Friendship Is Magic television series, the plot involves
Twilight Sparkle pursuing her stolen crown into an alternate world, where she transforms into a humanoid teenage girl.
While learning how to behave locally, Twilight encounters the parallel universe
counterparts of her pony friends, who join her in the search for her crown.
My Little Pony: Equestria Girls premiered at the Los Angeles Film Festival on June 15, 2013, and entered limited
release in the United States and Canada on June 16, followed by a home media release on August 6.
The film received mixed reviews, with most criticism directed at the
character design, writing, plot, and characterization.
It was followed by three sequels, Rainbow Rocks (2014), Friendship Games (2015) and
Legend of Everfree (2016) – all of which were more positively received.
The film explores themes of princess, high school, friendship, magic, villain.
The tone is lighthearted.